good afternoon Hello
добрый день Здравствуйте
Kazan Russia Tatar Yes support the special operation
Казань Россия татарин Да спецоперацию
no war I don’t support and
поддержите нет войны не поддерживаю а
who is to blame for the fact that Russia attacked
кто виноват в том что Россия напал на
Ukraine
Украину
many who,
много кто
including Ukrainians and Russians, are
в том числе и украинцы и русские
coolly
прикольно
guilty that you attacked us explain there
виноват что вы напали на нас объяснить
was no such attack there was some kind of
не было такого нападения была какая-то
support precisely  In Eastern Ukraine,
поддержка именно Восточной Украины
Russia seized the Crimea and seized
Россия захватила Крым так и захватила
part of the Luhansk Donetsk region there is
часть Луганской Донецкой области есть
everything in the resolutions of the OSCE there is it Everything is
все в резолюциях обсе есть это Все
recorded as a result
записано в результате
[music] if you want to
[музыка]
read it to you now
хотите вам зачитаю сейчас
please
пожалуйста Нет я говорю то что
resolutions adopted at the
резолюции приняты на парламентской
OSCE Parliamentary Assembly at the 26th annual session
ассамблее обсе на 26 ежегодной сессии
Minsk 2017 July, so paragraph
Минск 2017 год июль так вот пункт
42 calls on the Russian Federation as the
42 призывает Российскую Федерацию как
occupying power on the Crimean
оккупирующую державу на Крымском
peninsula and then there you fix
полуострове и дальше там есть фиксируешь
what the West thinks about it wait
то что Запад об этом думает подожди
Russia signed the Minsk agreements
Россия подписала минские соглашения
Russia
Россия
3 parties signed Ukraine the OSCE and
3 стороны подписала Украина обсе и
Russia here we are listening to the OSCE as an arbiter
Россия вот мы слушаем обсе как арбитр
here we are listening to the OSCE about the Minsk
вот мы слушаем обсе про минские
agreements here 12 point we
соглашения вот 12 пункт принимаем
note that you specifically Russia does not
внимание что ты специально Россия не
appear in the Minsk agreements then
фигурирует в минских соглашениях затем
read 12
прочитать 12
including
видов военной техники в том числе
military
российских вооруженных сил военных
areas of the Donetsk Luhansk region of
районах Донецкой Луганской области
Ukraine not controlled by the government, which are exclusively in service with the Russian armed forces,
Украины не подконтрольных правительству
including areas in which the presence of
включая районы в которых присутствие
heavy weapons is prohibited by the Minsk
тяжелый вооружений запрещено минскими
agreements, we further
соглашениями дальше
emphasize that, according to the Minsk
подчеркиваем что Согласно минским
agreements, all hostages illegally
соглашениям все заложники незаконно
detained should be released,
удерживаем лица должны быть освобождены
including those who were illegally abducted from
включая лиц которые были похищены с
Ukrainian territory
украинской территории незаконно
continues to be held in Russia
удерживается в России дальше
Urgently urges the Russian
Настоятельно призывает Российскую
Federation to fully comply with its
Федерацию полностью соблюдать свои
obligations Under international law
обязательства По международному праву в
as an occupying power, so
качестве оккупирующие державы так вот
there is everything there absolutely There is now
есть все вот есть абсолютно Вот вот
calls on the Russian Federation to
призывает Российскую Федерацию
strictly comply with the norms and
неукоснительно соблюдать нормы и
principles of international law in principle
принципы международного права в принципе
obligations under the OSCE and the Minsk
обязательства в рамках обсе и минские
agreements, that is, clearly  it says that
соглашения то есть чётко говорится что
Russia does not comply with the Minsk agreements
Россия не соблюдает минские соглашения
Russia signed their
Россия подписала их
Minsk agreements They were just
минские соглашения Они же были именно
signed, uh, so that, well, firstly, there is
подписаны э-э чтобы ну во-первых там
part Well, the Donetsk Luhansk region, they
часть Ну Донецкой Луганской области они
would remain part of Ukraine,
оставались бы составе Украины
of course, the
конечно оставались
Minsk agreements remained on the website, the protocol is
на сайте минские соглашения протокол
therefore the consultations of the tripartite
поэтому консультации трехсторонней
group, so point 10  to withdraw illegal
группы так 10 пункт вывести незаконные
Armed formations military equipment,
Вооруженные формирования военную технику
as well as militants and mercenaries from the
а также боевиков и наемников с
territory of Ukraine to some country, they
территории Украины в какой-то страну
should have withdrawn,
должны были вывести
look, that is, militants from Ukraine, then
смотрите то есть боевиков с Украины то
there were Volunteers, I ask again,
там были Добровольцы я еще раз спрашиваю
look, withdraw illegal
вот смотрите вывести незаконный
Armed formations military equipment,
Вооруженные формирования военную технику
as well as militants and mercenaries from
а также боевиков и наемников с
territory of Ukraine to which territory On the territory of
территории Украины в какую На территории
which country they were supposed to be
какой страны они должны были быть
withdrawn
выведены
I don’t know the meaning I didn’t understand the essence of the issue
я не знаю смысле Я не понял суть вопроса
Well, look, you read it in the Minsk
Ну смотри вы читали это в минских
agreements it is written here is paragraph 10 to
соглашениях написано вот 10 пункт
withdraw illegal armed
вывести незаконные Вооруженные
formations of military equipment, as well as
формирования военную технику а также
militants and mercenaries from the territory of
боевиков и наемников с территории
Ukraine, who and  where I was supposed to withdraw
Украины кто и куда должен был вывести
these militants from the territory of Ukraine, but I
этих боевиков с территории Украины но я
understand that the armed equipment
так на вооруженная техника понятно там
was clearly Russian there, but the militants And who do they mean by the militants, you
русская была безусловно а боевиков А
need to ask who signed the Minsk
надо спросить кто подписал минские
agreements of the Russian Federation to Ukraine, he signed the music
соглашения РФ Украине мюзу он подписал
on behalf of Russia, he will agree what
от имени России он согласится то что по
you think To where they should  there were these militants
вашему До куда должны были эти бое виков
to bring them out on the territory Who and where they
вывести так на территории Кто и куда их
were supposed to take out Well,
должен был вывести
as I understand it, those
Ну я так понимаю боевиками назвали тех
who voluntarily arrived there were called militants Well,
кто там добровольно прибыл Ну
I ask no one militant, I will ask who they
я спрашиваю никто боевик я спрошу кто их
were supposed to take out and where, well, it
должен был вывести и куда ну а там
indicates where they need to be taken out Look
указано куда их нужно вывести Вот смотри
from the territory of Ukraine Well, it means that at least where
с территории Украины Ну значит хоть куда
possible as
можно
soon as possible there are three parties signed by
быстрее есть три стороны подписали
Ukraine Russia and the OSCE Which of these three
Украина Россия и обсе Кто из этих трех
parties was supposed to withdraw the militants from
сторон должен был вывести боевиков с
the territory of Ukraine
территории Украины
could and Ukraine could and Russia
могла и Украина могла и России
Ukraine should have taken some militants and
Украина должна была каких-то боевиков и
equipment to withdraw the territory of Ukraine to a
технику вывести территорию Украины в
foreign state
чужое государство
no, but the militants came from somewhere,
нет но боевики же откуда-то прибыли
right, look again, here is Ukraine, here is the
правильно еще раз смотри вот Украина вот
state of Ukraine, it can
Есть государство Украина она может
simply have militants in some foreign
боевиков просто в какой-то чужое
state, and it says that these are
государство а там написано что это
Russian militants again, I don’t
русские боевики еще раз я вас не
ask you whose glare is this, we don’t
спрашиваю чьи это блики мы сейчас не
say Whose We are  we ask here in Minsk
говорим Чьи Мы спрашиваем вот Минске
the agreement was signed by Three parties Yes
соглашения подписала Три стороны Да
Ukraine the OSCE and Russia Which of these parties
Украина обсе и Россия Кто из этих сторон
was supposed to fulfill the tenth point
должен был выполнить десятый пункт
to withdraw militants and equipment from the territory of
вывести боевиков и технику с территории
Ukraine I don’t know
Украины Я не знаю
Ukraine could not because it can’t
Украина не могла потому что она не может
take militants and equipment to a foreign country
да в чужую страну вывести боевиков и
how to deport like  militants militants
как депортировать типа боевиков боевиков
strange
странно
some country would take and withdraw
какую-то страну взяла бы и вывела
military equipment and militants remain
военных технику и боевиков остается
Russia, it turns out Russia should have
Россия то получается Россия должна была
withdrawn militants and equipment from the territory of Ukraine
с территории Украины вывести боевиков и
to its territory, I understand correctly Well,
технику на свою территорию я правильно
she could do this, but this must be
Ну она могла это сделать но это надо
understood by someone with a militant still  if even
понять кто-то при боевик еще раз даже
if these militants were there, here are the residents of
если эти боевики были там вот Жители
Ukraine who came in large numbers from Russia It doesn’t matter
Украины понаехавшие из России Не важно
who they are, so you signed the Minsk agreement you signed
кто они так вот Минский соглашение вы
Russia signed the Minsk agreements
минские соглашения Ну Россия от имени
obligations That is, it
она взяла на себя обязательства То есть
turns out that according to the tenth point, Russia
получается по десятому пункту Россия
was supposed to withdraw militants and equipment from the
должна была вывести боевиков и технику с
territory of Ukraine
территории Украины
Well, so maybe I don’t argue
Ну таким Так может быть я не спорю
Why are these militants like Russia They
Почему Как Россия эти боевики Они под
were controlled by Russia or not.
контролем были России или нет Вот этого
I don’t know
я не знаю
how then Russia if these militants are not
как тогда Россия если эти боевики не
controlled by Russia, how could she
подконтрольные России как она могла их
bring them out
вывести
? Well, somehow take control, look
Ну как-то взять под контроль смотрите
there. I’m not saying that there
там же Я же не говорю то что там русских
weren’t Russians there, look like that. Well, if there are
не было не такие смотри Ну если вот есть
three parties, for example, one
три стороны так например одна арбитр
OSCE arbiter and two opposing Ukraine and
обсе и две противоборствующие Украины и
Russia Yes, if they sign  up to which
Россия Да если подписывают до что
some troops should be withdrawn first
одни войска должны быть выведены первый
first they generally exist they alone
первый Они вообще есть они одни
do not have them at all three if so those that you
нет их вообще три если так те которые вы
call second they are 3 Well why do you
называете вторыми они 3 Ну почему ты все
call them all second and they did not put on the labels of
Называйте вторыми и они не одели метки
the agreement this is a set of measures to
соглашения это комплекс мер по
implement the protocol, that is, the first
выполнению протокола то есть первых
Minsk agreements  some and what you
минские соглашения одни а то что вы
call the second, they are three, and the third Yes,
называете вторым они в три а третий Да
this is a set of measures to prevent their implementation We
это комплекс мер по их не выполнения Мы
take
берем
the signed Yes, in the fourteenth year, the
подписанные Да вот в четырнадцатом году
very first This document and it is clearly
самый первый Этот документ и Четко
written
написано 10 я открыл на сайте обсе у
also mercenaries from the territory of Ukraine
также наем ников с территории Украины
Wait Just
Подождите Просто
as far as everyone already understands these Minsk
насколько уже всем понятно эти минские
agreements in general no one again
соглашения вообще никто еще раз еще раз
look again there is a document we now understand it is
смотрите есть документ мы сейчас понятно
not clear so like who was supposed to
непонятно так типа вот кто должен был
withdraw it turns out Ukraine could not
вывести получается Украина не могла
withdraw some other people to foreign territory in Russia
вывести на чужую территорию в России
military type and
вывести чужие какие-то военных типа и
equipment, everything is
технику все
still here, they are always against the war, you are
вот еще вот они всегда я против войны вы
to blame, too, yes, they unwound it like this
виноваты типа тоже да вот так размотали
because the strength of Ukraine’s arguments to
потому что сила аргументов Украины до
Ukraine The truth stands like this Because it is
Украины Правда стоит так Потому что есть
in all resolutions of the OSCE, that is, they
во всех резолюциях обсе то есть они
first refer to the OSCE, then Grisha
сначала ссылаются на обсе потом Гриша
is the opinion of the West  Dude, you yourself said
это мнение Запада Чувак ты сам сказал
the word obse you opened your mouth said obse I
слово обсе ты открыл рот сказал обсе я
opened parliamentary snot to you I
тебе открыл парламентская сопливость я
everything is clearly written Russia coupon and on the
все все четко написано Россия купон и на
territory of Donetsk Luhansk region
территории Донецкой Луганской области
too
тоже